Mariana A. Mendez

San Francisco, CA • (415) 619-7000 • marianaa.mendez4@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/marianaamendez website: marianamendez.me

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Passionate, committed, and enthusiastic professional dedicated to promoting health throughout entire communities. Qualified nutritionist with 5+ years of experience providing exceptional counseling and developing nutritional plans for patients from a variety of ethnic and socioeconomic backgrounds. Interested in working with nonprofit organizations that are focused on advocating for youth education and health, as well as eradicating extreme poverty and malnutrition among minorities and low-income populations.

EDUCATION

City College of San Francisco

Community Health Worker Certificate Youth Advocate Specialist Certificate

Universidad Autonoma del Noreste

Bachelor of Science, Clinical Nutrition (Official Title)

Study abroad: College of Marin, Marin County, CA Educational Approval Bachelor of Science, Clinical Nutrition

Expected: December 2019 Expected: December 2019

San Francisco, CA

Saltillo, Coahuila, Mexico

November 2017

January 2015- December 2016

May 2014

EXPERIENCE

Saint Mary's Medical Center

San Francisco, CA

October 2018 – January 2019

Dietitian Assistant Prepared and delivered presentations for private institutions promoting mindful eating and healthy lifestyle

Organized health records for the Registered Dietitian

Saltillo, Coahuila, México

Jan 2017-Aug 2017 Jan 2012 - Jan 2013

CIAC – Non-profit clinic for low-income populations **ISSSTE** – *Private hospital for government workers*

Nutritionist Intern

- Provided daily nutritional consultation for a variety of conditions to 20+ individuals and 10+ families per week
- Developed a streamlined system based on macronutrient intake that allows patients to design dynamic meal plans
- Designed individualized nutrition plans for hospital patients with unique dietary needs
- Conducted weekly health evaluations for diabetic and hypertensive patients
- Ensured safe meal preparation for hospital patients

Saltillo, Coahuila, México

Feb 2013- Nov 2014 Nov 2011 - Mar 2012

SIGMA Company

Nutritionist Intern

- Designed individualized healthy meal plans for John Deere employees
- Prepared and presented monthly talks about mindful eating and healthy lifestyle
- Managed food quality, food storage, and kitchen and staff sanitation
- Conducted inventory and placed orders to ensure continual replenishment of stock with minimal waste

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Skills in Nutrition field:

- Designing meal plans for patients who suffer from chronic illnesses
- Calculating daily caloric intake requirements
- Developing individualized meal plans and healthy habits
- Teaching healthy lifestyle and behavior change in individuals and families

General Skills:

- Public speaking
- Communicating with people from diverse backgrounds
- Fundraising to help impoverished populations

Languages:

- Spanish (Fluent)
- English (Fluent)
- Italian (Basic)

Volunteering:

Founder of a group that fundraises, prepares, and distributes healthy meals to the homeless in Saltillo, Mexico